嘿，大家好，我是TheCherno，欢迎回到我的游戏引擎系列
hey, what's up guys, my name is TheCherno, welcome back to my game engine series
那么上次我们看了Glad，如果你们还没看过那期视频，可以先去看看
so last time we took a look with Glad, if you guys haven't seen that video, check it out up there
Glad只是我们加载我们需要的现代OpenGL函数的一种方式
Glad was just a way for us to load kind of the modern OpenGL functions that we need
以便使用现代OpenGL作为我们渲染器的一部分
in order to use modern OpenGL as part of our renderer
这是非常重要的，今天也是时候把ImGui引入我们的引擎了
which is gonna be very important, now today it's finally time to get ImGui into our engine
所以在屏幕看到东西应该是第一个主要的事情，真的很酷
so this is the first major thing that will actually see on the screen, which is really cool
我想这将是我们渲染的第一种东西，同时也是我们未来开发的基础
it's gonna be the first kind of thing that we render I guess, and also the base is for a lot of our future development
因为这对于我们能够正确调试非常重要
because this is gonna be absolutely vital for us to be able to debug things properly
只是在屏幕上显示信息，甚至ui这些东西，所以我真的很兴奋能引入这个
just display information on the screen and even uis and just all of that stuff, so I'm really excited about getting this in
只要我们能把它引入进去感觉就更像引擎了
there's gonna feel a lot more like an engine as soon as we can get this in there
我们还会看到很多非常关键的事情，我们可能需要在未来做，让这个实现更合适
and also we're going to see a lot of really critical things that we need to maybe do in the future to make this implementation more proper
因为今天我们要做的是一个叫做hack的东西，如果你们熟悉软件开发是如何工作的
because today what we're going to do is something called a hack, now if you guys are familiar with how kind of software development works
我的意思是，我相信你们在某种程度上是，我甚至会在下面链接一篇文章
I mean, I'm sure you are to some extent is, I might even link an article below about kind of
有几种不同的开发软件的方法，尤其是其中一种开发软件的方法
a few different ways of I guess how you can write software, particularly there's one way of writing software
第一步就是让它跑起来，然后让它运行正确，对吧，让它没有问题
which is the first thing is kind of make it work, the second one is kind of make it like correct, right, make it right
然后最后一步就是为了让它更快，好了，那么我们先直接让它跑起来吧
and then the last one, the last step is kind of just to make it fast, okay, so we're gonna be kind of just making it work
我们要把所有东西都hack进去，因为我想在屏幕上看到ImGui
we're just gonna hack everything in, because I want to see ImGui on the screen
那就是我今天要讲的内容，很简单，我们会想尽一切办法做到这一点
that's how I go by the end of today, it's pretty simple, we're gonna by any means to get there
我们只要hack进去，就会成功的，很明显，我不会让它变得很糟糕
we're just gonna hack it in, we're gonna make it work, I'm not gonna, obviously, make it horrible
但我们要让它变得有用，好了，现在他们正在做正确的一步就是正确地抽象一切
but we're going to make it kind of usable, okay, now they're making it right step is kind of abstracting everything properly
而不是使用原始的OpenGL函数调用，这是我们今天要做的
so that instead of using raw OpenGL function calls, which is what we're going to do today
整个ImGui渲染器通过Hazel的渲染器，这意味着它告诉Hazel
the entire ImGui renderer goes through Hazel's Renderer, which means that it tells Hazel
这儿有个渲染三角形，这儿有个渲染文本，我想要渲染这个，我想要渲染那个
here one render a triangle, here one render text, I want to render this, I want to render that
对吧，而不是实际依赖OpenGL
right, instead of actually relying on OpenGL
不过那要等很久，因为我们没有渲染器，对吧，我们需要先有一个渲染器
that's gonna be way later, because we don't have a renderer, yeah right, we need to have a renderer first
然后我们就可以实现那个了，但我想在我们有渲染器之前引入ImGui
and then we can do that, but I want ImGui in before we have a renderer
这样我们就能在编写渲染器时调试它，然后实现所有那些好东西
so that we actually can debug our renderer as we write it, and do all of that good stuff
这样做会容易得多，最后一步就是让它变得更快，我的意思是，不，反正它应该很快
it's gonna be a lot easier to do that this way, I'm the last to make it fast, I mean, no, it should just be fast anyway
但重点是，那就是我们现在的情况，这将是一个hack
but the point is that's kind of where we're out right now, this is gonna be a hack
但我们会在这期视频的最后把ImGui引入Hazel，所以我很兴奋，让我们开始实现它
but it's we're gonna get ImGui to Hazel by the end of this video, so I'm pretty excited, let's pop over and start making this happen
好了，那么第一件事是，我已经拷贝ImGui仓库相当长时间了
okay, so the first thing is, I have forked ImGui quite a while ago
已经为它创建了一个premake文件
and I made a premake file for it
那么这和使用GLFW是一样的，你们可以看到，这就是我的premake文件，非常简单
so this is the same kind of thing as with GLFW, you can see, there is my premake file, it is pretty simple
和往常一样，因为premake很棒
as always, because premake is great
不过这儿还有一些制表符和空格之类的原因，缩进也有一些问题
there's a few problems with indentation as usual, because of tabs and spaces whatever
但我真的需要修复那个问题，我认为GLFW也有同样的问题
but I really need to fix that, I think the GLFW thing has the same issue as well
我还认为，不，不，这确实有那个问题，很好
and also I think, no no, this does have supervision ladies, good
不像GLFW，不管怎样，我们有这个，将把它作为子模块添加到我们的git仓库中
unlike GLFW, anyway, we have this, we're gonna add this as a sub module to our git repository
所以就在这儿，在C:/dev/Hazel中，也就是Hazel所在的地方，我要执行git submodule add
so over here, inside C:/dev/Hazel, which is where Hazel is for me, I'm just gonna do git submodule add
现在我不记得语法了，我想，它应该先是仓库地址，然后是所在路径
now I actually don't remember the syntax, I think, it's the repository and in the path
就是那样，然后路径是Hazel/vendor/ImGui，就像那样
so that's the thing, and then the path in which we'll put this is Hazel/vendor/ImGui just like that
我不知道，如果我应该，不，不会做任何大写，让我们这样做，好了，然后一旦那个完成
I don't know, if I should, no, we won't do any capitalization, let's just do that, okay, and then once that is done
我们应该能够进入Hazel并打开我们的premake文件，我将把ImGui添加到其中
we should be able to go into Hazel and open our premake file, and I'm just going to add ImGui into that
所以就像我们所有其他的包含目录一样，我也要为ImGui创建一个
so just like we have with all of our other include directories, I'm going to make one for ImGui
这将是Hazel/vendor/ImGui，我们实际上可能应该看看这个，老实说，这可能是我们需要的
which will be Hazel/vendor/ImGui, and we actually should probably look at this, yeah that's probably all we need, to be honest
然后我们会用到imgui.h，那已经包含了，因为它根本不在包含目录中
and then we're gonna just do imgui.h, that'll include that, because this is not inside an include directory at all
好了，我要复制这个，把它放到包含目录的末尾，也就是ImGui
so that's fine, I'm gonna grab this and chuck it on the end of include directories, ImGui
然后我们还需要链接它，当然，如果我们看一下ImGui的premake文件
and then also we need to link it, and of course I've got, if we actually look at the ImGui premake file
你们可以看到，它和其他库一样，是一个静态库，好了，漂亮
you can see that, of course we've got it as a static library like everything else, okay, fantastic
所以现在如果我们返回，我们应该能够生成我们的项目，完成，重新加载解决方案
so now if we go back, we should just be able to generate our projects, done, reload the solution
当然，我们这里没有ImGui，因为我忘记了一个最重要的部分，那就是像这样包含它
and of course we don't actually have ImGui in here, because I forgot one of the most important parts, which is to actually include it like this
那么现在再次生成我们的项目，好了，一切都完成了，现在我们有了ImGui
so now generate our projects again, there we go everything is done, we now have ImGui over here
让我们试着构建它，好了，所以当然，构建成功了，Hazel应该像它那样引用它
let's try and build it, okay, so of course that succeeded, and a Hazel should reference it as it does
好了，漂亮，一切都完成了，那么现在我们需要做的最重要的事情就是是设置ImGui层
okay, fantastic, everything is done, so now the biggest thing we need to do is set up the ImGui layer
为了实现那个，我们需要创建一个新文件，那么让我们进入Sandbox
now to do that, we're actually gonna have to make a new file, so let's come into Sandbox
哦，抱歉，现在让我们把Sandbox放到Hazel中，然后我们现在得到的是
oh sorry, now let's Sandbox into Hazel, and then what we've got is at the moment
我们在Hazel里面已经有了所有的东西，那很酷，但我想做的是，如果在这儿显示所有文件
we've kind of got everything inside Hazel, that's cool, but what I want to do is if I show all files here
在Hazel里面，我一直在测试是否要这么做，是否
inside Hazel, I've been testing out whether or not to do this, whether or not
我们需要把它放在一个叫做debug的文件夹中，我想是在Hazel开发分支中
we want to actually put this into a folder called debug, I think in the Hazel development branch
我确实把它放到了一个叫debug的文件夹里，因为我总是，我想像是一个debug
I did actually put it into a folder called debug, because I'm always kind of, I guess like a debug thing
现在我要为它创建一个名为ImGui的文件夹，然后创建一个头文件和一个cpp文件
for now though I am actually going to just make a folder called ImGui for it, and then make a header file and a cpp file
叫做ImGuiLayer，现在的问题是，我不认为它只是用来调试的
I guess called ImGuiLayer, now the thing is I don't really think that it is something that's just gonna be used for debug
例如，我的意思是，因为Hazel是一个，它不像一个应用框架
for example, I mean, since Hazel is quite a, it's not really like an application framework
我甚至不知道我们是否会创建自己的ui库，因为那个需要很多工作
I don't even know if we will end up kind of creating our own ui library, because that's a lot of work
如果我们像ImGui那样，你们知道为什么，为什么我们会浪费所有的时间去实现那个
and if we what ImGui, you know like why why why would we kind of waste all of all of that time kind of trying to do that
所以那是我的思路，因为再说一次，如果我们
so that's kind of my line of thinking, because again, if we were making like
我想这是一种专业的游戏引擎，我们可能希望拥有自己的ui
this was like a professional kind of game engine I guess like we probably would want our own ui thing
而是因为我觉得至少现在是这样，除非有人真的想要
but because like I feel like maybe for now at least unless someone really wants it
你们可以很好地配置ImGui来做你们想做的任何事情
you can probably just configure ImGui pretty well to do pretty much anything you want
因为它是一个非常好的小ui库，好了，所以ImGuiLayer非常简单
because it's quite a nice, it really is quite a nice little ui library, okay, so ImGuiLayer pretty simple
我们会有一个构造函数和一个析构函数，然后我们可能会重写一堆东西
we're gonna have a constructor and a destructor, and then we're gonna probably override a bunch of stuff
我们有内层，所以很酷的是我们已经有了，我们可能真正需要的这两个
that we have inside layer, so the cool thing about this is that we already have, what we really probably need on these two
我们已经有了一个事件系统，这真的很有用，因为我当然会用到很多事件
we already have an event system, which is really useful, because of course I'm going to use a lot of events
所以那就是我喜欢做这个的部分原因，让我们包含我们的hzpch.h和ImGuiLayer.h
so that's part of the reason why I just love doing this, let's include our pch and include ImGuiLayer
命名空间Hazel，我们将从所有东西创建方法实现
namespace Hazel, and we're going to just create method implementations from everything
好了，酷，往上滚动，我将调用这里最好的构造函数，带一个名字
okay, cool, so scrolling up, I'm going to just call the best constructor here with a name
我们将使用的名字是ImGuiLayer，所以这或多或少会是一种带有Hazel的ImGuiLayer
so the name that we'll use is ImGuiLayer, so this is more or less going to be the kind of ImGuiLayer that comes with hazel
那么你们可以在任何层上开始渲染ImGui，我不知道我们要怎么设置
so you can obviously just start rendering ImGui probably on any layer, I don't know how we'll set that up
但这是一个特定的层，我们会在这里进行调试，这是我们的调试绘图层
but this is like a specific layer, where we're going to render kind of debug things, this is like our debug draw layer
这个总是会被绘制在我们30个场景的顶部(？？？)
this will always be drawn kind of a last or rather on top of our 30 scene and all of that
那么是了，这将是一个特定的层，我们可能会在其中调用ImGui之类的代码
so yes, it's going to be a specific layer in which we probably will end up calling ImGui kind of code
或者至少可以在上面绘制任何ImGui类型的窗口
or at least being able to draw any ImGui kind of windows on this
所以我们甚至可能最终添加像ImGui绘图或其他图层
so we might even end up adding like an ImGui draw or whatever to like other layers
我不知道该怎么设置，我们可以晚点再谈，好了
I don't know how we're gonna set that up, we can talk about that later, okay
所以我实际上想做的是某些初始化代码，但我认为它可能会依赖于OpenGL
so what I actually do want to do is certain initialization code, but I think it's going to probably rely on OpenGL
所以我要做的是，我想做一些事情
so what I'm going to do, well there's a few things that I want to do
但我想做的第一件事实际上可能是复制OnAttach和OnDetach
but the first thing I want to do is actually probably end up taking OnAttach OnDetach
因为我知道，很明显，当添加一个层时，它肯定已经有渲染器设置了
because I know that obviously, when a layer is attached, it will already, it definitely should already have the renderer setup
那么OnAttach和OnDetach，我们也会为这些创建方法实现
so OnAttach OnDetach, we'll create method implementations for those as well
它最后是否又创建了一个，是的，我创建了
did it end up creating one more, yeah I did
我不知道为什么要这样做，在OnAttach和OnDetach中，我们需要做一些很重要的事情
I'm not sure why did that,okay, so inside OnAttach OnDetach, we need to do a few really important things
所以为了知道我们实际需要做什么，我将进入Hazel/vendor/ImGui
so to know what we actually need to do, what I'm going to do is go into Hazel/vendor/ImGui
然后我们会看一些例子，这里有两个例子是我想重点关注的
and then we're gonna look at some of the examples, so there's two examples that I want to focus on
一个是opengl3的实现，也就是这个，我们会复制那个，并保留它
one is kind of the opengl3 implementation which is this, so we'll grab that, and we'll keep that around
另一个是glfw的实现，那么就是这个
and then the other thing is the GLFW one, so this one
好了，那么那就是我们今天要讲的基础
okay, so that's kind of going to be the basis for what we're actually going to do today
这个opengl3，它实现所有这些gl的东西，我们基本上会完全复制这个
now this opengl3 thing, which does all of this gl stuff, we're basically going to copy this completely
好了，那么我就把它放在Platform里面，在Platform中，创建一个新建项
okay, so I'm gonna put it into Platform, inside Platform, I'm gonna make a new item
抱歉，是一个叫OpenGL的新文件夹，然后我要做的是
sorry, a new folder called OpenGL, called OpenGL, and then what I'm going to do is
实际上，我要直接复制粘贴这些文件
I'm actually going to end up copying and pasting these files just directly
甚至不可能，甚至不打算重新命名它们，只是为了让我们真正强调，它们是暂时的
not even probably, not even going to rename them, just so that we really do reinforce the fact, that they are temporary
我们要把它们放在这里，并把它们包含在我们的项目中，现在我们可能需要改变一些东西
and we're going to put them in here, and include them in our project, now we probably will have to change a few things
但我们会看到如何进行，所以这是我们的直接实现，那么至于这个imgui.h
but we'll kind of see how we go, so this is like our direct implementation, so imgui.h
我的意思是，我觉得那应该没问题，我不确定为什么不行，好了，那么这个东西
I mean I think that actually should be fine, I'm not sure why that's not, okay, so this this stuff uh
我的意思是，要把这个去掉，因为这是我们自己的文件，我们会重命名它，这样我们就没有
look, I mean, I'm just gonna strip this out, because it's our own file, we will rename this, just so that we have there's no
没有任何冲突，那么我们就叫它ImGuiOpenGLRenderer，还有那个也是
there's no kind of confusion, so ImGuiOpenGLRenderer of what we'll call this, and that as well
我们会看到我们在这里做了什么，那么清楚地定义？，那很奇怪，把imgui.h包含在这儿
and we will see what we do here, so clearly define ???, that's weird, well, include imgui.h in here
我不知道为什么我不喜欢，我不喜欢这个，不管如何，反正它对这个不满意
I'm not sure why I'm not, I don't like that, it's not happy with this anyway
然后我们还必须，在我们包含其他东西之前，我们还需要包含pch
and then we also have to, before we include anything else, we also need to include our pch
我们可能会马上重新生成项目，这实际上应该没什么问题
we'll probably have to regenerate projects as well in a minute, and this actually should be fine
我想那可能只是VS的问题，不，它确实没有包含那个
I think that might just be visual Studio, no, it really can't include it
嗯，那很奇怪，因为它应该是一个包含目录，它在Hazel里面，所以那有点奇怪
huh well that's weird, because it should be an include directory, and it is inside Hazel, so that's a little bit weir
让我们快速检查一下包含目录到底是什么，vendor/ImGui/include
let's just quickly check what the include directories actually are, vendor/ImGui/include
那是错误的，因为它只是vendor/ImGui，所以如果回到Hazel，并打开那个premake文件
ah well that's wrong, because it's just vendor/ImGui, so if we go back to Hazel and grab that premake file
我们要确保这里没有像那个的路径，然后我们会再次生成我们的项目，好了，搞定，重载
we're just gonna make sure that this does not something like that, and then we'll generate our projects again, okay, done, reload
好了，酷，那么现在已经完成了，让我们再次尝试构建我们的渲染器，看看得到了什么
okay, cool, so now that we've done that, let's try and build our our renderer again, and we'll see what we get
好了，这儿还有一些错误
alright, few errors here
好了，显然它可以包含这个，因为我们把它改成了ImGuiOpenGLRenderer
okay, this it can include obviously, because we've changed this to be ImGuiOpenGLRenderer
然后它对其他一些东西不爽，因为我们没有包含Glad，所以先包含Glad
and then it's not happy with a bunch of other things, because of course we're not including Glad, so we'll include Glad
好了，成功了，漂亮，那么搞定，现在回到ImGuiLayer这边
okay, succeeded, fantastic, so that's done, now back in ImGuiLayer land
我们可以在OnAttach中做一些我们需要的事情，那么这里我将包含两个文件
we're going to be able to OnAttach do a bunch of things that we need, so I'm going to include two things into here
我将包含ImGuiOpenGLRenderer，它实际上在Hazel/Platform中
I'm going to include the OpenGLRenderer, which is actually in Hazel/Platform
我认为这实际上也包含ImGui本身，但我可能也应该包括imgui.h
and I think that actually includes ImGui itself as well, but I probably should just include imgui.h as well
好了，它对这个不爽，有点奇怪，让我们在Platform中，看起来是Platform/OpenGL
okay, so it's not happy with this, and that's a bit weird, oh it's not unheated, let's just in Platform,  looks Platform OpenGL
好了，酷，那么OnAttach，有一些ImGui的事情我们需要做，比如你们知道的CreateContext
okay, great, so OnAttach, there's a few ImGui things we have to do, such as you know CreateContext
现在这些东西应该写在这里，它们都消失了，那很好，我不知道它们为什么消失了
now this stuff should be written by the way in here, they're all gone, that's great, I don't know why they disappeared
我刚刚点击关闭了标签，所以那挺好的，但如果我们再次进入examples目录，会看到GLFW
I was just clicking on the minute was closing the tabs, so that's great, but if we go into examples again, and we'll look at GLFW
所以我们有了所有这些我们可能关心的回调，以及所有内部代码
so we have all these callbacks that we probably care about, as well as all the internationalization code
比如CreateContext，我甚至不知道它在哪里，我想它可能在
such as CreateContext, which I don't even know where that is, I guess that's probably in yeah
所以ImGui关于这个的很多实现可能在example_glfw_opengl3中
so the other thing that ImGui does is a bunch of this stuff is actually probably in, like example_glfw_opengl3
在这个main.cpp文件中，那么你们就可以看到它实现了CreateContext以及很多这些功能
inside this main file, yeah so you can see it does CreateContext and all of this stuff
现在我已经知道我在做什么了，因为之前实现过这个，但你们知道，那就是我引用的东西
now I already know what I'm doing, because I've implemented this before, but just so you know, that's kind of what I'm referencing
那么这儿这个main文件，在你们使用到的例子中，也就是这两个示例文件
so there's the main file, that's inside the example you're using, there's the two example files
比如example_glfw.h和example_glfw.cpp，还有OpenGLRenderer之类的实现例子
which is like example_glfw.h and cpp, and there's also the renderer at the OpenGL kind of implementation example as well
所以那就是opengl3，所以那就是我的想法，在此基础上，我们要写所有这些东西
so opengl3, so that's kind of the idea, and based on that, we're just gonna write all this stuff
那么我们会创建上下文，这里我们会使用深色，然后我们需要做的是设置一些标志
so we're gonna create the context, we're gonna use dark colors here, and then what we need to do is set some flags
那么就是ImGuiIO& io = ImGui::GetIO()，我们会设置一些BackendFlags
so I'll see ImGuiIO equals ImGui::GetIO(), we're gonna send, we're gonna set some BackendFlags
这就像是发送的，ImGui设置代码一样，那么就是HasMouseCursors，是了
this is just like pretty sended, ImGui set up code, so HasMouseCursors, yes
最终我们还需要添加一些光标，可能不是今天，因为它就像是hack实现一样
we have to add a bunch of mouse cursors as well eventually, probably not today, because it's like the hack implementation
HasSetMousePos，好了，如果我们想让按键运行，就需要建立一个按键映射
and HasSetMousePos, okay, and then what we actually need to do, if we want keys to work is set up a key map
现在我认为这是在这里的东西，所以我不需要把它写出来，在哪儿来着
now I think that this is something that is inside here, so that I don't have to write everything out, where is it
那是OpenGL实现，我在找GLFW那个，好了，找到了
all right, that's the OpenGL implementation, I'm looking for the GLFW one, okay, there's that came out
我们只是要复制这个，现在这是非常暂时的，我实际上要
we're just gonna steal this, now this is extremely temporary, and I'm actually gonna
temporary最终会用到Hazel按键代码，我们可能会在下期视频中看到Hazel按键代码
and temporary should eventually use Hazel key codes, and we might actually take a look at Hazel key code stuff in the next video
因为那很重要，我需要这样做，就像输入轮询系统
because that's important, I need to be done, as well as like an input kind of polling system as well
因为现在我们有一个事件系统，但如果我想问输入，嘿，这个按键按下了吗
because right now we have an event system, but if I want to actually ask the input, hey, is this key down
我们现在还不能这样做，所以需要去做，好了，那么就是GLFW/glfw3.h，当然也是暂时的
we can't do that right now, so we need to go to do that, okay, so GLFW/glfw3, of course this is also temporary
我们不应该在这里包含glfw3，但就像我说的，这是一期hack视频
we should not be including glfw3 here, but as I said this is a hack video
至于ClipboardText，我想我们现在不需要考虑，然后我们需要做的另一个实际上是
this stuff ClipboardText, I think we won't worry about for now, and then the other thing we need to do is actually
一旦我们完成了那就是初始化这个OpenGL，它在OpenGL中
once we've done that is initialize this OpenGL thing, which in it for OpenGL
我想这里还有一个不同的，就是OpenGL3_Init，我想这是我们想要的
I think there's a different one there, yeah OpenGL3_Init, now I think that's what we want
然后我们想要的版本，我们现在用的可能是410，好了，酷
and then the version that we want, and that we'll use for now is probably going to be 410, all right, cool
所以希望那最终能初始化成正确的gl版本，这是我们想要的
so hopefully that actually ends up initializing with the correctional gl version, which is what we want
我很确定现在应该是这样，就更新而言，我们想要做的实际上就是每一帧
and I'm pretty sure that should be yet, so as far as updating goes, and what we want to actually do every frame
重要的是ImGui::Render，我认为，打开Renderer，那么就是NewFrame和RenderDrawData
the important one is of course ImGui::Render, as well as I think, show Renderer, so NewFrame and also RenderDrawData
所以我们需要调用NewFrame，我想我们首先调用ImGui::NewFrame实现那个
so we need to do NewFrame, and I think we do that first followed by ImGui::NewFrame
然后我们调用Render，然后还需要调用RenderDrawData
and we do Render, and then also we need to do the RenderDrawData
然后从那里，我们会从ImGui获得绘制数据，好了，酷
and then from there, we'll actually get the draw data from ImGui, okay, cool
就是这样，我们要做的是，快速创建这个静态变量(show)，值是true
that's it, what we will do is, I'll just quickly write this, static true
这将决定是否显示演示窗口，也就是ShowDemoWindow
this will just whether or not to show this demo window, which about ShowDemoWindow
所以我们会显示一个演示窗口，它的名字是ImGui演示窗口，它有我们想要的一切
so we'll show a demo window, which shall be kind of just a, it's the name ImGui demo window, that has everything we might want
现在我们还需要设置delta时间，所以可以从GLFW中得到它，我认为GetTime会返回双精度
now we need to set the delta time as well, so we can get that from the GLFW, I think that returns to double GetTime
是的，它会返回一个双精度，然后我们会设置io.Delta时间，那么就是ImGuiIO
yes, it does return a double, and then we'll set io.Delta time, so ImGuiIO
这是什么，就是ImGuiIO& io = ImGui::GetIO()，这个io.DeltaTime =
what is this, um ImGuiIO& io equals ImGui::GetIO(), and this will be io.DeltaTime equals
我们需要记录时间，所以我们会看到m_Time，然后是time-m_Time，否则就是1/60
we'll have to keep track of our time, so we'll see m_Time time minus m_Time, otherwise we'll do 1/60
以防m_Time还没有设置，然后添加属性float m_Time = 0，所以这就是首帧会执行的
so just in case m_Time is not set yet, and then we'll do float m_Time equals zero, so the first frame it will just do
它只是1/60，好了，酷，不管怎样，那只是一个非常基本的实现
it'll just do one over sixty, okay, cool, anyway, that's just a very basic implementation
不管怎样，就像我说的，我们可能会重写这个，也就是m_Time=time
anyway, as I said, we'll probably rewrite this, we'll set m_Time time
好了，所以那应该是我们需要的所有东西
okay, great, so that should be everything that we need
还需要设置DisplaySize吗，现在的Application，我想没有Window，我们需要的是Window
are we also need to set the DisplaySize, now Application, I think doesn't have a Window, and what we need is Window
我认为有GetWidth()和GetHeight()，好了，我们要做的是返回这个Window
I think has a GetWidth, GetHeight, okay, so what we'll do is we'll return this Window here
我们要做的只是创建一个inline Window& GetWindow()，它会像那样返回Window
so what we'll do is just an inline Window&, GetWindow, which would return window just like that
然后在这里，因为我们想设置的主要东西就是DisplaySize
and then over here, we will, because the primary thing that we want to set is something called DisplaySize
它告诉ImGui显示是怎样的，为了实现那个，需要得到我们的Application
which just tells ImGui how video display is, so to make that happen, we'll need to get our Application
我们现在还没有，我想我们有的，好了，那么Application现在不是单例的，那是一个问题
we don't have that at the moment, I thought we did, okay, so Application is not a singleton at the moment, that's kind of an issue
所以我们要做的是需要得到Application，这儿添加一个s_Instance，这应该是私有的
so what we want to do is basically have Application, I'll add s_Instance here, this should be private
这应该是我们有的东西，因为Application，只会有一个Application
this should be something that we have, because Application, it's only going to be one Application
不管在哪儿，不管在代码中什么位置，我们都可能需要访问Application
and wherever we are, just types out wherever we are in our code base, we will probably want to access the Application
因为它有重要的信息，它的作用是，为我们的Application持有一个单例
because it has important information, so what this will basically do is, hold a singleton to our Application
它在我们构造Application时设置，我们应该只有一个，所以甚至可以断言，以确保你们知道
which gets set when we construct our Application, and we should only have one anyway, so we could even assert to make sure that you know
我们只能有一个Application，所以也就是s_Instance需要为空，Application已经存在
that we only have one Application, so what to see s_Instance needs to be null, Application already exists
我还有一个s_Instance，这样无论在代码库中，比如这里，我们可以看到Application::Get()
I also have a s_Instance to this, so that then wherever we are in our code base, such as here we can just see Application::Get()
那会返回我们Application，那么让我们包含Hazel/Application.h吧
and that will kind of give us our Application, so let's include Hazel/Application
就是Application::Get()，Get()需要是静态的，好了，酷，那么现在我们得到了了这个
Application::Get, Get needs to be static, okay, cool, so now that we have this
我们可以在这里放入app.GetWindow().GetWidth()和app.GetWindow().GetHeight()
we can into here just put app.GetWindow().GetWidth() and app.GetWindow().GetHeight()
好了，酷，那我们继续，我想就是这样了，我们当然也要实现事件，但我认为那应该是
alright, cool, so there we go, I think it's about it, so we have to do events as well of course, but I think that should be
那应该差不多了，我们需要让这个运行起来，所以我很想看看它能不能跑起来
that should be pretty much, all that we need to actually get this running, so I'm interested to see this will work
因为这只是一些hack的东西，那么如果我们进入我们的SandboxApp
because of course, this was a lot of just hacking stuff in, so if we go into our SandboxApp
现在，我们只有ExampleLayer被推送进去了，但我要做的是
at the moment, we only have our ExampleLayer being pushed in, but what I'm gonna do is
我要进入Hazel.h，添加Hazel/ImGui/ImGuiLayer.h
I'm going to into into Hazel.h, I'm just going to add in Hazel/ImGui/ImGuiLayer.h
然后在我们的SandboxApp中，我将推送一个覆盖层，也就是我们的ImGuiLayer
and then in our SandboxApp, I'm going to push an overlay, which is going to be our ImGuiLayer
好了，那么那是不存在的，ImGuiLayer，那应该是合法的，哦，是了，它必须在Hazel里面
okay, so that is for some reason not there, ImGuiLayer, that should be legit, oh well yeah it has to be inside Hazel
我以为我们在命名空间里，好了，酷，现在我有点害怕，让我们按f5，看看会发生什么
I thought we were inside the namespace, okay, cool, so now I'm kind of scared, but let's hit f5 and see what happens
我可能会在这里放一个断点，因为我想检查某些东西看它们是否设置正确
I'm just gonna put a break point maybe here, because I want to check out certain things to see if they were set correctly
它没有一个奇怪的。。。有一个链接错误，因为没有ImGui，让我们展示给你们看看
okay, so it's not having a weird certain, we got a linking error, because we're missing ImGui, let's show you guys
因为我们忽略了，似乎我们忽略了构造函数，它没有参数
because we're missing, it seems we're missing the constructor, that has no parameters
那有点奇怪，因为不是那个，看看ImGuiLayer，显然我们忽略了这个，怎么忽略了那个
that's a bit weird, because is that not it, ImGuiLayer, we're missing this apparently, how does we're missing that
我们忘记导出了，那么就是HAZEL_API，所以那很重要的
oh well I mean we actually forgot to export it, so what is it HAZEL_API, so that's kind of important
别忘了，好了，那么我们得到了一个调试错误，abort被调用了，这些都是最好的
let's not forget that, okay, so we have a debug error, abort has been called these are the best ones
所以ImGui不爽，如果我点击重试，ImGui不爽是因为我们没有调用CreateContext之类的
so ImGui's not happy, if I hit retry, I can see, ImGui's not happy, because we didn't call CreateContext or anything like that
我认为那可能是因为，当我们附加层的时候，它们实际上是没用的
I actually think that maybe, that's because yeah when we attach layers, they don't actually, you know cause
那么这儿应该是layer->OnAttach()，PushOverlay中也一样，我们再试一次
so layer->OnAttach is what should happen here, and in PushOverlay, so yes let's try that again
好吧，它又不爽了，这次是无效的DisplaySize值，好了，酷，我有种感觉
okay, it's not happy again, this time invalid DisplaySize value, okay, cool, so I have a feeling
让我们快速看一下这些很酷的东西看看，这是从OnUpdate GetIO哪儿冒出来的，好了，知道了
let's just look at the cool staff quickly to see, where this is coming from OnUpdate GetIO, ok, alright, okay
我想我们之前应该做过那个，所以在开始创建新帧之前，我们需要设置一个大小
I think that maybe we should have done that before, so before we begin the frame, we actually need to set a size
那么我们会像那样实现那个，实际上会先做计时，所以需要把这个移下来
so we'll do that like that, and actually we'll even do the timing first, so we'll need to move this down
好了，那么我们继续，DisplaySize已经被设置成了1280x720，很好，DeltaTime是0.016s
okay, so there we go, DisplaySize has been set to 1280 by 720, that's great, DeltaTime is 16 miles seconds
让我们看看得到了什么，好了，看看，太棒了，这里就是ImGui，我们不能移动任何东西
let's see what we get, oh okay, look at that, fantastic, so we have ImGui here, we can't move anything
我们不能追踪任何东西，因为我们没有事件
we can't track with anything, because we have no events
但这是多么酷啊，我们在窗口有了ImGui渲染
but how cool is this we have ImGui rendering inside our window
那非常棒，好了，所以下一步就是设置所有的事件
that's pretty awesome, okay, so the next step would be to set up all of the events
现在我将把它作为一个练习留给你们，看看你们是否能自己弄明白
now I'm going to leave this as a bit of an exercise to you guys to see if you guys can figure it out by yourselves
我们将在下期视频中做，因为这期视频已经有30分钟了，但我会看到这个
we're going to do this in the next video, because this video's already like 30min, but I will see this
如果只是引用这个GLFW实现，你们可以看到实际发生的是
if you just reference this implementation, the GLFW has, you can see that what actually happens is
如果我们看一些KeyCallback函数，你们就可以看到实际发生了什么，对吧
if we look at some kind of you know KeyCallback function, you can see what actually happens, right
所以我们调用这个回调，也就是MouseButtonCallback，那个KeyCallback在哪儿
so what we call this previous callback, which is as a MouseButtonCallback, where's that KeyCallback
你们可以看到它设置io，也就是ImGuiIO，我们基本上想要设置某些变量
yeah you can see that it sets io stuff sometimes that ImGuiIO, we basically want to set certain variables
所以你们知道的，当我们按下一个按键时，它会将KeysDown[key]设置为true，对吧
so you know when we press a key, it sets KeysDown with a relevant key to true, right
或者对于直接修改它取决于是否被按下，对吧，对于鼠标位置
or it for modifiers it sets directly whether or not they're pressed, right, for the mouse position
例如这儿有个MouseButtonCallback，我相信它会在循环中完成
for example there's a MouseButtonCallback, which actually this gets done inside a loop I believe
那么io.MouseDown会在UpdateMousePosAndButtons中被设置
yeah so io.MouseDown gets set inside the UpdateMousePosAndButtons
所以如果你们引用这个imgui_impl_glfw文件，应该能够设置一切
so if you refer to this imgui_impl_glfw file, you should be able to get everything set up
非常简单，非常简单，对吧，所以那就留给你们当作练习吧，看看能不能实现
really easy, really easily, right, so that's kind of an exercise for you guys to see if you can do
但下周我会向你们展示我是怎么做的，我们会让ImGui完全互动和运行起来
but otherwise next week of course I will show you guys how I do it, and we'll get ImGui fully kind of interactive and working
我们可能还会做光标之类的东西，因为这个文件中有很多东西需要做
and we'll probably do things like mouse cursors as well, because there's quite a lot of stuff in this file, that needs to be done
我绝对不想在这期视频中匆忙完成，希望你们喜欢这期视频，如果喜欢，就为它点赞吧
and I definitely don't want to rush it in this video, hope you guys enjoyed this video, if you did, hit the like button
一如既往地感谢所有支持本系列节目的赞助人
huge thank you as always to all the patreons that make this series possible
如果你们没有在patreon上支持我，一定要去看看，它真的对支持这个系列有帮助
if you guys aren't supporting me on patreon, and definitely check it out there, it really does help support the series
你们现在就可以看到下期视频，因为它已经上线了
also you'll get to see the next video right now, because it's already up
还有所有这些东西所有ImGui的东西，所有的代码都已经在开发分支中写好了
and also also all of this stuff all the same ImGui stuff, all the code has already been written in the development branch
你们也会看到，因为我在那里写了更多Hazel的代码
that you will get access to as well, because I've got like much more of Hazel actually written there
那么如果你们有兴趣提前离开，不想等的话，那就去看看patreon.com/thecherno吧
so if you're interested in kind of just leaving ahead, and you don't want to wait, then check out, check out patreon.com/thecherno
希望你们喜欢这期视频，如果喜欢的话，就为它点赞吧
hope you guys enjoyed this video, if you did, please hit the like button
现在能在屏幕上看到实际的东西是非常令人兴奋的，尽管这有点小技巧
it's really exciting to see the actual stuff on the screen now, even though this is a bit of a hack
我们将来需要重构很多，我认为实际的层基本没问题
and we'll have to refactor a lot of it in the future, the actual layer stuff I think is mostly okay
它就是渲染器，那才是我们需要完成的重要事情
it's the Renderer, is the really big thing that we'll need to work on
一旦Hazel真的有了自己的渲染器，不管怎样，我们下次见，拜
once Hazel actually does have its own Renderer, anyway, I'll see you guys next time, goodbye